# **ANDREW TYLER CALKINS**

atcalkins.github.io | tylercalkins89@gmail.com | 240.483.7247

#### **SKILL SUMMARY**

10+ years experience in small business to large corporation environments. Able to work proactively independently or as part of a team within web development, consultative sales, recruiting, and marketing. Demonstrated leadership and vital communication skills in numerous industries. Responsive to new roles and relentless in the pursuit of further knowledge and providing maximum value. Ambitious to refine technical skills and learn industry standards.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, Node.JS, Passport, MongoDB, Mongoose, Express, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Bootstrap, JSON API, Mustache, Test Driven Development, Agile Development, HTML, CSS, Git, Github, Microsoft Office, Slack

#### **RELEVANT EXPERIENCE**

**TM Associates** | Gaithersburg, MD, Present

**Technical Support and Marketing** 

- IT Support of a small commercial real estate office
- Develop and implement marketing initiatives
- Manage database for traditional marketing outreach and manage social platforms

#### The Iron Yard | Washington D.C. 2017

The Iron Yard is a 12-week coding boot camp specializing in highly focused, immersive training centered on programing language fluency, object-oriented programming, and project-based learning. Gained extensive knowledge in a full stack curriculum with a focus of Ruby on Rails.

- Question Box Ruby on Rails project that made use of group pull requests and reviews, and stored user submitted questions and answers with search functionality, tags, pagination and bootstrap styling.
- **iTunes Music Search** Front- end project using JavaScript, HTML, CSS and the iTunes API to allow a user to search for an artist. Users can then select the album artwork for each song, and listen to a preview.

# Hilton Worldwide | Charleston, SC 2016 - 2017

Sales Coordinator

- Produced leads and contracts for corporate accounts, events, and groups of various sizes.
- Maintained database of leads, signed contracts, and paid accounts.
- Exceeded forecasted sales goals consistently while assisting various departments.

### Federal Consulting Resources | Gaithersburg, MD 2015 – 2016

Search Consultant

- Identified, interviewed, and qualified technical candidates for positions primarily in the defense sector.
- Maintained client and candidate information in company wide database.

# Mt Airy Heating & Air Conditioning | Mt Airy, MD 2006 – 2016

Install/Marketing/Sales

- Oversaw installation and repairs of heat pumps, air conditioning units, and furnaces.
- Diversified marketing efforts through social media outlets, company site, and postcard mailings.
- Improved profitability through multiple marketing outlets, and outstanding customer service.

# **EDUCATION**

Coastal Carolina University | Conway, South Carolina 2013

Bachelor of Science in Recreation and Sport Management

- Minor in Business Administration.
- Event planning internship with Elite Tournaments in Columbia, MD.